SodaComp is a soda company
based in Bonn, Germany.
SodaComp's CEO has set an aggressive target:
to grow its European market share by 3%
by the end of the year —
which is just five months away.
A marketing team has been working away
on the problem for several weeks.
First, they defined the problem
and have been using their problem question —
“How can SodaComp improve its European
market share by 3% by the end of the year?”
— to guide their thinking.
The team drilled down on their problem question,
identified a number of issues,
and hypothesised about
how they might be addressed.
They prioritised two issues
and their associated hypotheses
that they feel are central to addressing
the question of market share growth.
Number one: to improve
their channel strategy.
And number two: to innovate
with regard to product development.
The team has shared this issue tree, and the research
and thinking that went into it, with SodaComp's CEO,
who is pleased with their progress and is confident
the team has identified and prioritised
the issues that are most important to consider,
and come up with strong hypotheses.
The CEO has asked the team to move forward,
and the team is now considering
what their next steps might be.